So now that we've talked about all this,
let's take a look at the code that we've been building.
So if you go ahead and look at our types right now,
you might notice that both the dish and the restaurant type
share this property called status.
And more importantly, status is just a string.
When a lot of us know that when it comes to letting users
choose something, it's best to have some sort of options
that they consistently use.
And so if we go ahead and take a look back
at our restaurant's page and take a look at it.
So we can see here that, okay, status is,
we have want to try and recommend it.
Do not recommend, okay.
And then dishes page, similarly, there's want to try,
recommend it, do not recommend.
Okay, so now this is where we're seeing a use case
for having shared types and more importantly,
we want something that's a little bit more specific
than just generic string type that we have.
So we're gonna learn now is learn how to define those things.
So the way we're gonna do this is I'm just gonna call it
a type of status.
Let's just gonna call it.
And what we're gonna learn about here is the union operator
which basically allows you to define specific values
for the type rather than just a generic,
like data primitive or whatever.
So in this case, we had, I think it was want to try.
I think it was recommend and then I think it was
do not recommend.
Okay.
And so then what we can do here is rather than just
putting the generic string, we can actually say,
oh, this is gonna be a type status.
And what that allows you to do now is that when you hover
over this, you can see that it actually tells you
the exact ones that it allows.
Now if we go back over now to our page,
you'll notice something kind of funny.
Status is yelling at us.
And the reason for this is because it's saying,
hey, I don't recognize this value.
In other words, when it says something's overloaded,
usually doesn't recognize the value.
And it's saying, what is recommended?
And so I'm like, well, I thought I'd define it
as recommended, but let's go ahead and check the logbook.
Nope, we didn't, we called it recommend.
And so it's little things like this that can make a huge
difference for helping to start putting really
some shape to your application when it comes to like, okay,
this is the information architecture we're looking for.
These are the options we want to limit people to.
And so in this case, I think recommended is better
than recommend, because that was a type one my end.
And so now if I save it, you'll see that that just
automatically transposes over and same deal.
Now on the Dishes page, if I go ahead and I'm like, oh,
I think Dishes should also get like a delicious status.
You know, like that's fine that I did that,
but then at ways I get maybe it's not,
because it's not actually matching, right?
We want them to, like at this point,
we want them to share just a little bit easier.
So this is, and so you see something that's simple
is just creating that custom type.
And then dropping it between the two,
we see already, there's a ton of benefit.
Especially when these types are reused multiple times
throughout your codebase, now you're getting those alerts
that like, hey, this property you're adding
doesn't exist or has the wrong types now,
and we can get even more specific.
Okay, so we've now created our own custom type.
And so I want you all to practice creating your own custom type.
And what we're gonna be doing is I want you to create a diet.
So actually, I forgot.
I have this constant file here to give some guidance,
as far as what this might be.
So basically, you know, when it comes to eating food,
dietary restrictions are a thing.
So I just created four options to keep it simple.
There's vegetarian, pescatarian, keto, and then there's blank.
Cause some of them just, you know,
if it's like everything, then it doesn't matter.
And so I'd like you to create your own custom type.
Don't worry about referring to the constants,
let's just reference the values,
because we'll be taking care of that in the next one.